Samarth Samaiya (1) Featured

Senior Consultant seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Change Management, Technical Architecture, SAP Implementation, Project Management, System Analysis, Requirement Gathering, MySQL, Oracle, Apache Tomcat



Current Designation: Senior Consultant - IT Total Experience: 8 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Capgemini Notice Period: 15 Days or less

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Senior Consultant, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, Change Management, Technical Architecture, SAP Implementation, Project Management, System Analysis, Requirement

Gathering, MySQL, Oracle, Apache Tomcat

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 19-Jan-21 Last Modified: 19-Jan-21

Summary

Working as Senior Consultant with Capgemini India with 8 years of good experience in IT Industry.

Worked on Application Interface Framework (AIF) with Proxy & IDOC.

Worked in Inbound/Outbound Proxy & IDOC.

Worked on Enhancement/BADI.

Implement a SAP NOTE.

Worked on BDC method on specific scenario.

Familiar with technical/functional Documentation of objects.

Worked on Smart forms in support project.

Well Experienced in SAP reports.

Handle Module Pool scenarios

Having in good knowledge of data dictionary objects.

Familiar with debugging tool.

Worked as a Release Manager and handled Release management activities (Change Management Activity).

Having experience in resolve the incidents (tickets): P1/P2 issue on given time period.

Team Worker with good interpersonal, communication and fast learning skills.

Work Experience

Capgemini as Senior Consultant - IT

Jan 2019 to Till Date

Project Name: Schneider Electric Project Dates: Feb-2019 to Present Designation: Senior Consultant

Project Description:

Schneider Electric SE is a French multinational corporation headquartered in Rueil-Malmaison, France. It is also based at the World Trade Center of Grenoble. Schneider Electric is a Fortune Global 500 company, publicly traded on the Euronext Exchange, and is a component of the Euro Stoxx 50 stock market index.

Roles and Responsibilities:

Handling deployment as a Release Manager in change management activity.

Handling Change request and incidents. Developed an Inbound/Outbound Idoc's.

Worked in user exist and enhancement.

Worked in BDC method.

Worked on SAP note.

Worked in Smartforms and reports.

Build a technical specifications and Technical unit testing documents on all objects

Capgemini as Senior Consultant - IT

Jan 2019 to Jan 2019

Senior ConsultantProject Name: Schneider Electric Project Dates: Feb-2019 to Present Designation: Senior Consultant Project Description: Schneider Electric SE is a French multinational corporation headquartered in Rueil-Malmaison, France. It is also based at the World Trade Center of Grenoble. Schneider Electric is a Fortune Global 500 company, publicly traded on the Euronext Exchange, and is a component of the Euro Stoxx 50 stock market index. Roles and Responsibilities: Handling deployment as a Release Manager in change management activity. Handling Change request and incidents. Developed an Inbound/Outbound Idoc's. Worked in user exist and enhancement. Worked in BDC method. Worked on SAP note. Worked in Smartforms and reports. Build a technical specifications and Technical unit testing documents on all objects

Atos India Pvt. Ltd as Consultant

Jul 2016 to Jan 2019

Project Name: TripleS

Project Dates: Apr-2017 to Dec-2018 Designation: Associate Consultant

Roles and Responsibilities:

Worked in SAP SCRIPT/ Smartforms. Worked on ABAP Remediation access. Handling Change request and incidents.

Developed some user exist and done enhancement. Handle the UAT defects, Bug fix, CRQ, Incidents.

Worked in Report's.

Deploying the code and debug.

Wipro Technologies as Associate Consultant

Feb 2012 to Jul 2016

Project Name: Brooks Brothers Project Dates: JUL-2015 to July-2016 Designation: Associate Consultant

Project Description:

Brooks Brothers is the oldest men's clothier in the United States and is headquartered on Madison Avenue in Manhattan, New. Founded in 1818 as a family business, the privately owned company is owned by the Italian Billionaire, Claudio Del Vecchio, and now also features clothing for women.

Roles and Responsibilities:

Developed Inbound/outbound Idoc and debugged it.

Familiar with FMS implementation.

Developed a Proxy interface and configured with proxy.

Developed some user exist and done enhancement.

Configured with AIF and handle issues with AIF.

Created test cases to make sure the data is correctly populated in to the DW.

Build a technical specifications and Technical unit testing documents on all objects.

Education

UG: BCA (Computers) from Government Narmada Mahavidyalaya in 2008

PG: MCA (Computers) from Samrat Ashok Technology Institution in 2011

IT Skills

1/22/2021 **Skill Name** Version Last Used Experience ABAP 4 ALE Idoc, RFC, Message Control BADI, Proxy

ORACLE, MYSQL

Menu painter, Screen Painter, ALV Grid

Apache/Tomcat.

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				

Affirmative Action

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time